e
e e
[Music]
thank you Mr chair president excuse me
um I'm calling the order to order Langer
city council finance committee meeting
for September 23rd
2024 the first item to discuss is
resolution
10-24 a resolution to approve a then and
now certificate for payment of an
invoice from American structure point
out of the l l do Improvement fund
314 and this is coming from Public Works
uh councilman tener yes I'll have uh Tim
if you'd like to come up and explain
this oh I'm sorry was it
Jeff Jeff were you the I'm
sorry I can usually find
people but Tim you can just stay for the
next one then I'll stay for the next one
thank and Jeff be assistant city
engineer is uh with this resolution or
what what happened was we uh had a
resolution to enter into a contract and
encumber the money which which passed
but after that we did not cut a PO and
we proceeded with the work and we've
gotten the first invoice and we realized
that a PO had been cut but there's
already been a resolution to um you to
hire the consultant and to encumber the
money my second will be uh Mrs kites
thank you there any question any other
questions thank
you we're having a suspension oh yes I'm
so sorry suspension any objections to
suspension thank you next item for the
agenda is temporary resolution 101-2
24 a resolution to authorize the service
safety director to advertise for bids
and enter into contracts for mowing and
trimming the city cemetery this is
coming from public works also and
councilman Tiner please yes this is just
our our usual mowing they go out for bid
I'll let go ahead and let Tim
explain yeah this is an annual piece we
do every year um what we're trying to do
this year though is get a couple months
jump on the bid process um this year the
drought's kind
of put our mowers in a bind and they're
chopping it a bit to get a new contract
for next year so um soon as we can get
this pass we'll go out to bed hopefully
in November and get contract signed
before the end of the year and hopefully
uh we'll have a good budget number then
going into next year um if we need need
to do any cutting we can do it in that
line item so uh we can get this passed
we'll get this out the bid and we'll go
from
there okay three readings and Mr lenberg
will be my second yep can we turn the PA
up is that possible we can't hear yeah
we're having a hard time hearing with
the M turn on fan noise is the mic
turned on is it
turned I could we just we'll just ask
the people there you go people make sure
that they're close to the mic this
evening because we do have a lot of fan
noise because of air circulation going
on thank
you next one is temporary resolution
10224 resolution to approve the city of
Lancaster Cedar Hill Neighborhood area
plan coming from C coming from code
enforcement and
zoning and um two issues there uh
councilman a alers is not here and they
also had me for a second I'm not on the
committee so uh who is here from that
committee okay as am I I'm on Code
Enforcement you take it will you be this
will you be the second Mr L I'll
second okay good evening I'll be doing a
presentation on this shortly but um this
is just our Cedar Hill plan the
revitalization of the Cedar Hill area
and um it did go through Planning
Commission in
June
okay have me
reading three three three three
readings all righty any
questions thank you
excuse me next we have temporary
resolution 103-2
4 a resolution to authorize the law
director to negotiate and enter into a
contract with the city of Reynoldsburg
for the prosecution of adult Miser
traffic and criminal offenses committed
in the city of
Reynoldsburg um we have total three
resolutions coming up uh 103 104
105 representing different areas of the
county and um I assume law director
would like to talk about it sure thank
you chairman wolfinger I can address all
three of them at once safe time yep so
my office uh prosecutes all adult
misdemeanor crimes that occur in
Fairfield County and I do that for the
city of Lancaster by Statute but I also
do it for the city of Reynoldsburg the
city of Pickerington and all of the
unincorporated areas in the county by
contract we have three different
prosecution contracts one with
Pickerington one with Reynoldsburg and
then the County Commissioners pay for
everything that happens in the
unincorporated areas including the
townships and Villages so for
Pickerington and Reynoldsburg we
typically go on an annual basis because
their contracts can vary in terms of how
many cases they have that my office has
to handle in any given year um the
county tends to be a little bit more
predictable so we go on a 2-year cycle
with the county and currently all three
are up for a new contract term um
typically what we try to do is to ask um
those organizations to Bear a similar
responsibility for the costs of their
cases that we're Prosecuting um
ultimately the city of Lancaster
subsidizes my office because all of that
money goes into the general fund um all
of the proceeds of these contracts go
straight to the general fund nothing
comes to my office specifically um but
obviously you fund me out of the general
fund so would just appreciate you um
passing these so that I can start
negotiating those contracts and getting
those in place for
2025 sorry thank you excuse me thank you
and we got three readings on each of
those and any questions from anybody on
this one excuse
me all
right the final one is temporary
resolution
10624 a resolution to schedule Lancaster
City Council meetings and finance
committee meetings for
2025 coming from the law committee uh
councilman cres yes thank you um this
just sets those council meeting dates
for next year um because the clerk has
to get the the room scheduled and
reserved and I will be the second it
looks like yes in three readings three
readings thank you any questions from
Council you like the dates everybody
happy with them
good that concludes the resolutions I
and there's no ordinances for tonight
new ordinances for
discussion um under other discussion
items uh departmental
updates um I just wanted to make a quick
statement I know you guys are uh voting
on the third reading of the gas prepaid
deal so um I just prepared a quick
little something since 2008 the prepaid
transaction has been a vital source of
Economic Development funding for our
city currently we are kneed deep in this
transaction we've ramped up our
collaboration with Bond councel many
attorneys uh we're collaborating weekly
we're now we're now working really twice
weekly at least um as we we approach the
bond sale date um our lawyers and
advisers are working hard updating the
necessary documents and assessing the
market to ensure everything's in place
so with tonight's vote uh we sign we
significantly enhance the likelihood of
a successful deal uh this timing is
crucial as Financial spreads and rates
fluctuate rapidly sometimes by the
minute it's not even that it it is as
dramatic as that sounds uh so by getting
along period of time to capture the best
possible Trigger Time We position
ourselves to optimize our financial
outcomes we anticipate that the renewal
process will be finalized in the coming
weeks I thank you for your support um of
Economic Development funding uh through
this important program your vote tonight
makes a meaningful impact on our
community's growth and
prosperity any
questions I think we got the message all
right good thank you
any other department departmental
updates hearing none um I will move to
president Porter for tonight's uh
meeting prep yes this evening we have a
special presentation from our city
planner chasn Carter and Holly Maddie
regarding this Cedar Hill Neighborhood
plan you heard that alluded to a little
bit ago um we are going outside of the
order of regular business in order to
get our voting pattern in which is more
abbreviated than we normally have but it
is very important as previously
mentioned um that we get the prepaid gas
deal approved this evening in a in an
orderly fashion so that we can get that
out uh for purposes of dealing with the
interest rates and the changes that are
going on so um those are the two main
things and we will also be dealing uh
with our um Regular agenda um and going
through all of that as well thank you
thank you president
Porter um any other items for the
finance committee
anybody I hear
none and I would entertain a motion uh
adjournment motion to
adjourn okay I need to do a roll call uh
Mr alss yes Mr alers is not here Mr
skover yes and I vote Yes this meeting
is
adjourned thank you chairman wolfinger
612 thank you the regular meeting of
Lancaster City Council has to convene at
6:30 which was the public published time
we will do that that between now and
6:30 if folks need a restroom break or
or anything else we'll be on recess
until
630 so the restrooms are out in the
hallway if you haven't already seen
them thank
you the Frankie Smith Funeral Home in
cremator in Lancaster and the Johnson
Smith Funeral Home in Baltimore have a
long and wonderful history of serving
our community feel free to give us a
call at
0652 stop in and see us at either of our
two locations 405 North Columbus Street
in Lancaster and 207 South Main Street
in Baltimore respect for tradition
regard for
[Music]
change hi this is Chuck Sims with the
Lancaster dare program dare provide
students with skills to resist the
pressure of drugs gangs and violence and
emphasizes self-esteem good decision
making and communication skills this
month when you buy a car truck or SUV
from Buckeye Toyota or Buckeye Honda the
Buckeye cares program will make a
generous donation to DARE with every
vehicle they sell thanks Buckeye for
your continued support and helping keep
our kids
safe
e
e e
[Music]
good evening at this time we would ask
that you rise if you are able and
Gentlemen please remove your hats we
have a prayer before the meeting and we
roll into the Pledge of Allegiance thank
you God grant us the serenity to accept
the things that we cannot change the
courage to change the things we can and
finally for the wisdom to know the
difference I pledge Al to the flag of
the United States of America and the rep
for it stands one nation under God
indivisible with liy and justice for all
thank you you may be
seated I would ask now that the clerk
call the
role Mr
aers Mr here Mr BJ here Mrs here Mrs
here Mr lber here Mr SC here M here Mr
Wing here Mr
pres let the record reflect that nine
members of Lancaster City Council are
present at this time I would accept a
motion to excuse councilman aers Mr
President i' like to make that motion
second we have a motion in a second to
excuse councilman and haers all those
please signify by saying I their
approval I I all those oppose same sign
we will now uh have the reading and
disposal of the journal regular meeting
minutes dated September 9th
2024 Mr President I'd like to make a
motion to receive and file the journal
second we have a motion a second to
receive and file the journal all those
in favor please State I I I all those
oppose same sign we'll now move on to
the reports of City officials email
dated September 10th 2024 regarding
finance committee minutes submitted by
Mr wer email dat is September 13 2024
regarding an email response of
thewing show code violation submitted by
La email dat September 16th 2024
regarding yard waste disposal submitted
by superintendent sha Bor series of
emails dated October 18th including
Council
council president Porter Angela
PR and mayor's Administrative Assistant
Mrs she
regarding resing Council
training series of emails dated
September 19th
2024 council president reporter council
members and director Hall regarding
proposed schedule Council schedule email
dated September 19 2024 regarding Violet
toship proposal to amend the J submitted
by email date is September 20th 2024
regarding finance committee agenda
submitted by Mr the series of emails dat
September 23rd 2024 between chief police
chief CER Serv safy director Woody
Council and Council mation for counil
dated sep 23rd 23r
2024 series of emails dated September
23rd 2024
city council members and C
Administration Mr President I'd like to
make a motion to receive and file the
reports of City officials second we have
a motion second to receive and file the
reports of City officials all those in
favor please uh approve by saying I I
all those poose same sign we'll next
move on to
Communications in
SE excuse me thank you for providing us
that feedback but we would ask that
people don't speak out in the meeting if
you can't hear somebody please come up
and speak to the law director or
somebody over here on the end and they
they they will let us know we just need
to keep the business moving okay thank
you thank you sorry email dated
September 6 2024 regarding records
request on submitted paperwork on the
drag drag show
event held downtown submitted by Dan T
toolio email date is September 10th 2024
regarding resoning of type 2 annexation
submitted by David Hodge with Underhill
and Hodge LLC series of emails between
law director Hall council members and
Keith moger regarding drag show code
violations series of emails dated
September 16th
2024 between Robert nisle police chief
Snider law director Hall and council
members regarding Pride event that was
held on 9:14 2024
email dated September 18th regarding or
2024 regarding laner Pride 914 2024
event submitted by Natalie noes series
of emails dated September 19th 2024
between law director Hall assistant law
director Harden and Jennifer mock
regarding fundraising opportunities um
initiated by Jennifer mock email dated
September 20th 20124 regarding Ed 411 um
24 submitted by Stephanie Bosco with
Lancaster economic developer email dated
September 22 um 2024 regarding a letter
submitted to the members of the Council
on the light the night Pride event
submitted by Sarah comr email dated
September 22 2024 regarding personal
experiences of
um receiving support um submitted by
Melissa
McLaren Mr President i' like to make a
motion to receive and follow the
communications second we have a motion
and a second second to receive and file
the
communications um all those in favor
please by state I I all those post same
sign once again I would remind council
members to make sure your mics are we
receiving feedback from the audience
that they're having a hard time hearing
tonight's proceedings please move your
mics close to you please speak into
those mics uh when you're addressing a
particular issue I appreciate
everybody's cooperation
at this time we will move to special
presentations and this evening we have a
special presentation from our city
planner chasn Carter and Holly Maddie
regarding the Cedar Hill area
neighborhood plan if they would come
forward and do the presentation for us
are they going to
do I don't know necessarily that we
should turn on the lights people people
can
see Miss Carter the floor is
yours all right good evening president
Porter City Council Members committee
and guests I'm super excited that
everyone came out to hear about the
Cedar Hill plan
tonight um for anyone that has not had a
chance to see the plan and would like to
look at the proposed plan we have QR
codes over here on this table in the
yellow papers that you can download on
your
smartphones so thank you for letting us
present the finalized version of the
Cedar Hill Neighborhood area plan for
your
approval for those who do not know me my
name is chasn Carter and I took over the
city planner position at the end of
April a brief recap on how this plan
came to fruition my predecessor pH
Campbell and Holly Maddie owner of
Crossroads Community planning started
this project with the goal to revitalize
the state route 188 and US 22 quarter
coming into the city of
Lancaster to help advise and participate
in this plan a steering committee was
formed with the following
individuals the purpose of this plan is
to engage residents property owners and
and businesses within the target area to
create a shared Vision which would then
guide future development inform policy
and Zoning decisions and identify
possible opportunities for private
development it does not regulate
development activity change zoning of
properties or guarantee funding
implementation of any
recommendations as we all know a plan is
a tool that helps guide the decision-
making within a
community we hope that this plan will
help the city of Lancaster revitalized
an area of the city enriched in history
for which our town is best known glass
making let's get started with a brief
description of the study
area the area of focus was on portions
of State Route 188 or Cedar Hill Road in
us22 these two main roads intersect in
the study area and serve as major
entries into the city of Lancaster if
you look to figure if you look to the
figure on the presentation you will see
the study area extends just east past
North Ohio Avenue South of West malberry
Street West of Hawk the Hawking River to
Hunter Run and north of Lincoln Avenue
and martins's park a significant portion
of the study area lies within the flood
plane for the Hawking and Hunter runs
River the flood plane incorporates most
of the commercial areas along us22 and
State Route 188 which will impact the
values of the properties in this area
the average age of the buildings and
homes in the focused area date mostly
from pre1
1950 only 8% of the homes were built
after 1980 most of the pre-war housing
is about, 1500 to 2,000 square
ft the study area is made up of single
family homes with 15% of the housing
options featuring multif Family 2 to
four unit buildings the commercial and
Industrial corridors while functional
and in fair condition have aesthetic
challenges the primary businesses in
this area consist of independent and
small businesses such as Auto oriented
Services thrift shops and various other
personal services us22 is more
commercial with larger operations such
as national gas station chains and
smaller independent commercial
retailers and now I will hand it over to
the amazing Holly Maddie to dive into
planned content Holly
thank you so much uh as chazin said my
name is Holly N I'm with Crossroads
Community planning and our firm uh
assisted the city with this plan and I'm
going to take over and talk about the
plan content the goals and
recommendations so this plan um as chasn
mentioned um has a number of different
physical conditions that we have
outlined in the plan we Al o talk about
the demographics of the community uh and
then we also went out and did Behavior
mapping and data counts this included uh
staff from the city of Lancaster staff
from um Crossroads as well as some
volunteers going out and doing visual
data counts of different uh movements
and activities within the uh
neighborhood itself and we also utilize
data from L do OD do and other um
entities regarding traffic movements in
addition we did a community survey for
the neighborhood uh this survey had
postcards that were mailed to every
household within the neighborhood it was
also made available online and pushed
through social media it was not a survey
that was strictly uh limited to those
that lived in the neighborhood but what
we did was we um the first question
asked about the characteristics of the
person do they live in the neighborhood
do they work in the neighborhood do they
live and work in the neighborhood or do
were they totally somebody that just
passes through the neighborhood because
we know that we have a lot of
individuals that utilize that as a
corridor from us33 into Lancaster so
from that we were able to um divide the
survey results um between those who live
there and work there and those who just
pass through and able to analyze the
differences and the perceptions of those
um two categories which was was very
interesting in the viewpoints um of
those two different entities from there
we were able to create a guiding Vision
uh we were able to utilize the um key
words and the open-ended comments of the
uh survey to hone in on what was most
important to the residents within the
community as well as those traveling
through and uh we were able to create
that um vision and then from their goals
and recommendations so you could switch
to the slide um this is our vision
statement again uh this was created from
the keywords um throughout uh the survey
we also talked with the steering
committee um making sure that we um
understood what the steering committee's
thoughts were on this um so certain
words like multimodal um those those
words kind of raised to the top from the
steering committee um because it helps
set up for different types of Grants um
moving forward for the area so if we
keep us in suspense let's get to some of
the
recommendations thank you and so from
here um we had 10 goals um that had um a
series of recommendations with all 10
goals um so with this uh the most
important of these were um talking about
um sidewalks and gaps filling the
sidewalk gaps and adding pedestrian
Crossings um with this recommendation if
you see up in the top right hand Corner
um we have um the parking lot that is
near um uh Martin's Park and then also
has access onto
188 uh the recommendation coming out of
this goal was to improve um that parking
lot into a trail head um so that
individuals could utilize that lot it
could have an area for resting um for
bike way for bicyclist um and then also
could be used for overflow parking for
the park as well it talks about
realigning the um drive into that
Parkway to align with um Pierce Avenue
goal number two I'm not going to spend a
lot of time on um it had to do with food
trucks we got some mixed um results um
that through the community engagement
process so all we do is recommend in
this plan um to further study that to
understand the active active Corridor
through there goal number three is to um
maintain affordability that residents in
the study area currently appreciate
making sure that as we um look at
redeveloping properties that we are not
raising the property values to a point
where it's moving residents out and then
also sustaining and amplifying a
resident's sense of pride in their
community and then also providing
housing options um through the um with
the housing Supply and we also talk
about how a site that could specifically
be redeveloped into Workforce housing
and then two slides left um this one um
talks about the last of the goals um
talking about collaborating and
communicating with commercial property
owners um talking about Redevelopment
along that commercial Corridor in 188
maintaining the character of the
residential neighborhood while we focus
on redeveloping that commercial Corridor
as well as managing traffic with that
multimodal approach apprach and
maintaining Green Space through
Community Gardens and other um
recommendation recommendations such as
that and then finally communicating um
the vision and the goals to the
residents um and the business owners to
help them um understand different
programs that are available to help them
implement the recommendations and then
last but not least um just talking about
our historical connections um there is
um the gay fad um uh
Glass Museum was started by a woman in
um the you know 1950s it was a very um
diff difficult time for uh women at that
time she started her own business with
historical glass making this is actually
in the neighborhood um and there's
recommendations about broadening those
historical connections um to promote
small businesses in this glass city of
Lancaster so with that
take any question thank you thank you
Miss Maddie thank you Miss Carter do we
have any questions from Council Members
regarding the Cedar Hill um area
neighborhood
plan hearing none we thank you we note
that the legislation is on tonight for
first reading um if there are questions
we may have somebody come back during
the the course of getting through that
legislation sounds good thank you very
much
[Applause]
do we have any petitions and memorials
this evening there are no petitions or
memorials this evening thank you at this
time I would entertain a motion to go
outside the regular order of business to
move to the voting pattern Mr President
I'd like to make that motion second we
have a motion in a second to go outside
the regular order of business um all
those in favor please say I I I all
those opposed same
sign at this time we're going to move to
reading of resolutions beginning with
the third reading of resolutions with
temporary resolution
9624 a resolution to amend the
certificate of other sources and
Appropriations increase receipts and
appropriate from the unencumbered
balance in the police and fire Levy fund
2047 um submitted from Safety Committee
Mr bisj and Miss Tiner
M council member bisj thank you Mr
President I move that Council pass and
gross an enter upon the written record
resolution temporarily number 96- 24
second we have a motion and second to
pass and gross and enter upon the
written record temporary resolution
9624 any
discussion uh thank you Mr President
this is just enum uh encumbering $75,000
for overtime pay for our police officers
from summer events thank you any further
discussion hearing none please call the
RO uh Mr a or sorry Mr ALS yes Mr bisj
yes Mrs KES yes Mrs hoop yes Mr lenberg
yes Mrs Mr skover yes Miss tener yes Mr
Wing yes Mr wolfinger yes temporary
resolution
9624 passes 9 to0 temporary resolution
9824 a resolution to authorize the S
services safety director to enter into
to a contract for construction of the
South Water Plant concentrate booster B
pumps um project water water pollution
committee um Mr Wing and Miss tener
council member Wing thank you Mr
President I'd like to make a motion that
Council pass and gross and enter upon
the written record temporary resolution
number 9
9824 second we have a motion and second
to pass and gross and enter upon the
written record temporary resolution
9824 discussion council member Wing yes
thank you this for the additional
booster pumps at the South Water Plant
to handle concentrate line discharges
okay leaning thank you all right any
further
discussion hearing none please call the
role Mr ALS yes Mr bisj yes Mrs CH yes
Mrs hoop yes Mr luberg yes Mr skover yes
Miss tener yes Mr Wing yes Mr wolfinger
yes thank you temporary resolution 9824
passes 9 to0 no second reading ings
everybody all right we'll now move on to
First readings of resolutions with
temporary resolution 124 a resolution to
approve a then announced certificate for
payment of an invoice from American
structure point out of the L do
Improvement fund
3014 um from the public works committee
Miss Tiner and Mrs K council member
tener Mr President I'd like to make a
motion the council suspend its rules in
way the second and third reading of
temporary resolution
100-4 second we have a motion a second
to suspend the rules and wave the second
and third reading of temporary
resolution
124 council member Tiner any discussion
no thank you hearing none further on
further discussion please call the role
Mr ALS yes Mr bisj yes Mrs KES yes Mrs
hoop yes Mr lenberg yes Mr skover yes
Miss tener yes Mr Wing yes Mr wolfinger
yes motion to suspend the rules in way
of the second and third reading of
temporary resolution 124 passes 9 to0
council member tener Mr President I'd
like to make a motion to pass and ghost
and enter upon the written record
temporary resolution 124 second we have
a motion to Second pass and grow
entering upon the written record
temporary resolution 124 any discussion
council member no I think Jeff was here
earlier and nobody had any questions I
think we're good okay please call it
roll Mr alss yes Mr bisj yes Mrs yes Mrs
hoop yes Mr lenberg yes Mr skover yes M
Miss tener yes Mr Wing yes and Mr
wolfinger yes temporary resolution 124
passes 9 to0 temporary resolution
124 yo excuse me 10124 okay sorry a
resolution to authorize the service
safety director to advertise for bids
and enter in to contracts for mowing and
trimming the city cemeteries um Public
Works committee Miss tener Mr lenberg
council member Tiner first of three
readings please first first of three
readings on temporary resolution
10124 temporary resolution 102 24 a
resolution to approve the city of
Lancaster Cedar Hill Neighborhood area
plan um for with code enforcement and
zoning committee Mr aers and Mr lenberg
Mr lenberg
uh this will be the first of three
readings first of three readings on
temporary resolution
10224 temporary resolution
10324 a resolution to authorize the law
law director to negotiate and enter into
contract with the city of Reynoldsburg
for the prosecution of adult misdemeanor
traffic and criminal offenses committed
in the city of Reynoldsburg with um this
is with the finance committee Mr
wolfinger or Mr
aers council member wolfinger my might
we take and law director might we take
all three of those uh right now for
their their first readings is that up we
we do
that she only read one and she has to
actually read can we read all three and
deal with them at that or do we if yes
if she specifies the number and the
Preamble for each you can read them all
at once and then vote so so clerk Scott
would you read all three dealing with
the legal contracts please okay um
starting with 104
yes we read 10324 resolution temporary
10424 a resolution authorized the law
director to negotiate and enter into a
contract with the city of Pickerington
for the prosecution of adult misdemeanor
traffic and criminal offenses committed
in the city of Pickerington within fairf
County Ohio and to accept payment now
temporary resolution
10524 uh resolution temporary 10524
resolution to authorize the law director
to negotiate and enter into a contract
with a fairo County Board of
Commissioners for the prosecution of
adult Mr metanor traffic and criminal
offenses committed in The Villages and
unincorporated areas within farro County
Ohio and to accept payment um finance
committee Mr wolfinger Mr alers council
member wolfinger to be first of three
readings and all three resolutions thank
you council member wolfinger first of
three readings on temporary resolution
10324 10424 and
10524 temporary resolution
10624 a resolution to schedule the
Lancaster City Council me meetings and
finance committee meetings for 2025 this
is through the law committee and Mrs CR
Mr wolfinger council member CR yes thank
you this is the first of three readings
first of three readings on temporary
resolution
10624 we have now concluded the readings
of resolutions and move now to the
reading of ordinances beginning with the
third reading of temporary ordinance
3024 an ordinance authorizing the city
of Lancaster Ohio the city to enter into
an amendment to the natural gas supply
agreement a tax certificate or tax
regulatory agreement a bond purchasing
agreement and a continuing disclosure
agreement or commitment all as necessary
in any and all other agreements that may
be deemed necessary or appropriate the
agreements um number two authorizing the
use of certain financial and demographic
information of the city in the pre
preliminary official statement and an
official statement in continuing
disclosure in connection with the
issuance of revenue bonds by the
Lancaster Port Authority and number
three authorizing the payment of all
necessary Professional Services related
to the agreements the P preliminary
official statement and the official
statement all for the purpose of the
purchase and distribution of natural gas
by the city and related to the issuance
of revenue bonds by the port authority
to assist the city with its acquisition
of a supply of natural gas including
additional volumes for sale of the city
and to declare an emergency toare
declare an emergency thank you yes thank
you clerk Scott this is clerk Scott
second meeting folks I think she's doing
pretty well for this even bear with me
so council member
wolfinger I didn't hear that could you
repeat
that no me won't fight but we appreciate
it never get so Mr President I would
like to make a motion that Council pass
and grow and enter on a written record
resolution uh temporary resolution uh
30-24 orance sorry ordinance thank you
second we have a motion in a second to
pass and gross and enter upon the
written record temporary ordinance
3024 at this time I would just offer the
offer thanks to the law director our
Economic Development Department
everybody who's worked very very hard
council member wolfinger everybody who's
worked very hard to get this ordinance
across the line so thank you no need to
further discuss um Mr Bosco gave a great
introduction yes thank you U please call
the RO Mr Al yes Mr bisj Mrs K Mrs hoop
yes Mr lonberg yes Mr skun yes Miss
tener yes Mr wolfinger yes and Mr
wolfing and Mr Wing sorry yes temporary
ordinance
3024 passes 9 to0 second reading of
ordinance es beginning with temporary
ordinance
3324 in ordinance to authorize the mayor
to acquire five permanent drainage
easements necessary for the East Main
Street sewer separation and an Court
drainage improvements phase one project
um water water pollution committee Mr
Wing and Mr ALS council member Wing this
will be the second of three readings
please second of three readings on
temporary ordinance
3324 first reading of ordinances there
are none folks so we're done with
that so we are done with the reading of
ordinances and resolutions which
constitutes our voting pattern at this
time I would entertain a motion to go
back into our regular order of business
Mr President I'd like to make that
motion second so we have a motion a
second to go back into the regular order
of business all those in favor please
State I I I all those post same sign
thank you so at this time folks big
event we have reached uh the time for
permission of Voters and taxpayers I'm
going to give everybody the rules please
recognize we are here for public
discourse it is it's it's being
cooperative presenting your views to
council not any of the other folks in
the audience I know they're here they're
listening like you are but you're here
to present interviews Council council is
not this is not a question and answer
period it is for us to listen and we
will go about listening to everybody
this evening please keep in mind
speakers must be a resident or taxpayer
of the city of Lancaster they provided
your name and addresses for the record
we have that so we can make that
reflective in the in the minutes time is
limited to 3 minutes I will keep count I
hope apple is I hope Apple's right but I
think it might be um and um as I've said
all all comments should be directed
towards council at any time Council as
you've seen this evening can suspend its
rules conclude comment limit the number
of speakers or moove the time for public
comment should it deem it necessary to
conclude regular business so we are um
going to begin with public comment I
hope that you know which order you've
signed up in but I do believe law
director Hall has the the list for folks
and so we will begin public comment now
just let me pull up our
timer okay you be you may begin sir good
evening I am Thomas Pierce I reside on
East fth here within the city proper I
gladly pay taxes to the city for its
services I have and do serve on a number
of community boards to provide a better
quality of life for our citizens I am at
least a sixth generation of my family to
reside here within the city born and
raised here I moved away for college and
law school newly married my wife and I
chose to move back here to raise our
family Lancaster has been a wonderful
Community to grow up in and raise my
family after your last council meeting I
learned about a group whose only aim
seemed to be to suppress the free speech
of others I don't follow follow city
government closely I trust you to do the
right thing and if I have concerns
you'll hear from me tonight is one of
those times I watched your meeting
online and was appalled to see a group
of folks railing against a community
event called Light the Night of that
group of nine persons to address you in
opposition at least seven of those are
nine are Outsiders they do not reside in
the city nor pay taxes to the city as
residents and should have no say in how
my tax dollars are or are not spent to
support my city and to provide
engagement opportunities for my fellow
citizens I chose to attend light the
night and I saw love and respect and Joy
from participants what I saw from The
Outsiders and protesters was
intimidation and name calling one
protester proudly carrying and waving a
large Christian flag called a prominent
Community leader in attendance a
pedophile this is that is reprehensible
and disgusting and does not represent
Jesus as I know him that Community
leader is a state and nationally
recognized child welfare expert who has
spent the entirety of her career solely
in the service of protecting our
children other protesters appeared to be
walking throughout the crowd wearing
Second Amendment t-shirts and carrying
what appeared to be concealed weapons
however before the Second Amendment
comes the First Amendment and what I saw
was duly and appropriately expressed by
the participants at light the night I'll
end with this there are events at the
Bandstand or Fountain Square that do not
agree with however I don't complain to
the city that they can't or shouldn't
gather they have that constitutional
right just as it is their right to
gather to something I strongly oppose I
have the right not to attend I don't
protest threaten or intimidate those
groups because it offends me therefore I
will not stand idly by while Outsiders
and others try to tell me what I and my
fellow citizens of Lancaster can and
cannot participate in I deplore others
who believe they have the right to
choose for me they don't I choose for
myself that is freedom thank you for
your attention thank you
[Applause]
sir so folks folks I appreciate that
folks want to express their approval or
disapproval we have to keep the meing
going so if you could refrain from the
Applause um or talking over anybody I
would appreciate it we just want to want
people to be able to be heard and that's
what we're here for tonight okay folks I
appreciate you thank you um we'll now
move to our next speaker Mr Daniel
egitto that was a
guess my name is Daniel egov I live on
South High Street in downtown Lancaster
Ohio um you're going to hear a lot about
children tonight and how they're being
harmed and there are children being
harmed here but they're being harmed by
the hate it's taking homes from them
compared to other kids lgbtq kids are
four times more likely to be homeless
the leading cause of that homelessness
is being kicked out or having to flee
their their family home they've lived in
their whole life because someone there
is uncomfortable with them it's taking
their Futures 80% of lgbtq kids are
harassed at school because of their
identity they suffer verbal and physical
abuse from students sometimes from
teachers because of that they're more at
risk of failing classes having to repeat
grades and dropping out of school
completely than their
classmates it's taking their lives rates
of attempted suicide among lgbtq youth
are over three times higher than that in
other kids they're significantly more
likely to be bullied harassed physically
and sexually assaulted and when those
things happen to them they often don't
have anyone they feel they can trust to
tell the adults that are supposed to be
there for them are uncomfortable talking
about it so that's the kids we need to
be protecting the most marginalized
vulnerable people in our community kids
who suffer every single day because some
people are uncomfortable acknowledging
that they exist and those people
selfishly put their personal Comfort
over the safety of the children they use
as cover so when you ask me if kids are
being harmed yeah they are there were
kids at light the night who had to deal
the entire night with an uncomfortable
reminder that some people feel
uncomfortable about them and would
rather hate them than get over it like
adults so if it's really about the
children if you really care and you want
to protect kids start with the hate
thank you for your time
thank you we'll now move to our next
speaker Natalie
Curtis my name is Natalie and I live on
malberry Street Council Members I'm here
today to speak on behalf of a truly
remarkable group in our community the
rainbow Alliance of Fairfield County
this organization has done an
outstanding job in making our city feel
safe inclusive and welcoming to everyone
they've brought to Lancaster things I
never imagined that I would see through
their dedication and support we now have
pride in the most beautiful ways
imaginable the rainbow Alliance sponsors
countless family-friendly activities
bringing together people from all walks
of life to support one another the event
on Saturday September 14th was nothing
short of spectacular it moved me deeply
to realize how fortunate I am to witness
this part of our Town's history the Next
Generation my generation
now has the chance to walk through
downtown with their families feeling
safe and proud to be themselves to
experience Community individuality and
acceptance It's a reality I never
thought that I'd see in my hometown I
was raised Christian like many in this
community and today I value love Above
All Else what I experienced at late the
night was just that it was love
acceptance and pure joy the rainbow
Alliance has brought a wave of
inclusivity and kindness in our city for
which I am profoundly grateful
unfortunately even amid all the
positivity were there were those who
sought to bring negativity I saw the
protesters though they were silent and
peaceful their shirts displayed messages
of hate desite despite this I remain
steadfast in my beliefs it is my right
as a as a citizen of the United States
to follow my own path to believe in what
I choose and to raise my children in a
manner that aligns with those values I
am proud of who I am and I am thankful
to have a partner family and friends who
support me I am deeply thankful for the
rainbow Alliance and for the acceptance
that they have brought to Lancaster I
take pride in living in a community a
state and a nation where our beliefs are
our own and cannot be Stripped Away by
those trying to diminish the G the
dreams of the Next
Generation I find it perplexing that so
many people were upset by the event on
September 14th and event that was
entirely open to the entire Community
yet no one was obligated to be there
what's confusing is that in the same
town an event happens weekly at numerous
locations that don't Ally with my
beliefs or values and I choose not to
expose my children to them we simply opt
out of not attending a church service
yet I've never gone into a church
service mocked its attendees or shared
unauthorized videos of their children
online I respect that it is not my my
place to interfere with what others
choose for their families as it doesn't
impact my life instead of reacting with
hostility to things that we don't
understand why not make an effort to
educate our reached your three minute
limit please please conclude thank
you our next speaker
please president Porter the next
individual doesn't live inside the city
of Lancaster and I know you enacted
rules this evening indica that the the
speak must voters or taxpayers so I
didn't so if if that individual does not
we we will move to the next speaker
please uh okay the next speaker is Chuck
Berget how are you atted there I'm
sorry income tax okay okay well if if
the gentleman is is has been paying
income tax he can come up and take his
turn at the podium thank you sir sorry
just want to be safe it's okay and I
respect
that my name is Rick hansberger and I
have lived in and around Lancaster City
of Lancaster my entire
life among other things I am a social
influencer a community organizer and an
elected
official according to search Labs the
United States of America closely
estimates that 7.5% of the population
identify as
LGBT now when when you narrow that
search down to Ohio it drops to
4.3% and considering that Fairfield
County has been even more conservative
you can rest assured the percentage
Falls Way short of that right here in
our town yet here we are discussing the
fact that a minute portion of our
demographic seeks to get special
privileges and special treatment based
on an unfounded accusation that they
don't feel safe in our
community this is a ruse
I believe you already know this if the
LGBT community wants to have their
activities no one can Divi deny that
they have rights in this
country we all have friends and
relatives that pay the price for our
freedoms with their very lives and that
includes the LGBT
community what's in question here is the
people's right to be out in public
without the fear of encountering public
indecency we've been reassured by public
officials that even as recently as last
night these activities that took place
down at the Gazebo just N9 days ago
violated established public decency
laws my choice of sexuality is A Private
Matter so is
yours I'm not going to announce my sex
life to the world for many
reasons one of those reasons is that my
sexual preference does not define who I
am so categorically no one can Define
who they are based on their sexual
preference a person's identity is based
on their faith of choice and on their
ability to interact with others around
them and when I say faith of choice I'm
not making a spiritual statement I'm
making a factual statement because you
can have faith in
yourself if the LGB BT Community wants
to enjoy their freedoms that is the
choice they can make as American
citizens when the issue we seek Council
to weigh in on comes to
this how much display of someone else's
sexuality can be permitted in public
well the answer is
zero not just the LGBT community but
everyone in this room I'm not excluding
them I'm including every single person
here
so your choice here today is not to
decide one side or the other you reached
your three minute limit so I ask you to
conclude once again folks we' asked
everybody please we're trying to get
through and get to everybody that we can
I'm already here oh thank
you I'm I live at 346 booving Road in
Lancaster I was born and raised here uh
I am I am the executive director of the
Fairfield Family Forum and I am their
spokesman
um what is before the council is not
we're we were asking to look at the code
and see if within the code the things
that happened that Saturday lined up
with the code and and violated it or or
you know uh and so the question was what
is obscenity and obscenity the character
or quality of being obscene conduct
tending to corrupt the public morals by
its indecency loudness and that was
State versus fennington and US versus
Mel and that's right out of Black's Law
Dictionary fourth
edition
uh material obscenity is to the average
person applying contemporary Community
standards dominate dominant theme of
material taken as a whole appeals to the
puran interest if it is utterly without
redeeming social importance description
or representation if it is hardcore
pornography that was Roth versus United
States uh offenses to
chassity of minor to modesty expressing
or presenting to the mind or viewing
something that delicacy Purity and
decency forbids to be exposed calculate
the corrupt depraved and debauched the
morals of the people and to promote
violation of law ousness libidious and
tending to excite feelings of an impure
and unchaste
character tending to stir the sexual
impulses or to lead to sexual and pure
lustful thoughts tending to corrupt the
morals of Youth or to lower the
standards of the right and wrong
especially as to sexual relations that
was parmy versus United States and so I
went to the uh justice department
website and they still use Miller versus
California as their standard for what's
obscene and what's
not and uh currently there are 13 States
including Ohio that see this as a
potential problem within our communities
so it's not like there's a few of us
standing up trying to push back in my
own family I've lost members to
AIDS I have others in my family that are
of the homosexual Community
sorry and we don't shun them when they
come to visit we accept them we don't
agree with their lifestyle but we don't
shun them and we don't hate them no more
than we hate the opposing group that's
here tonight we want to love them as
Christ loved them so I yield back my
time thank you sir we now move on to the
next speaker Mr Mike
Welden thank you sir great thanks uh
Derek UT oops
hi my name is Derek UT um I don't know a
lot of you but a lot of you probably
know who I am I'm the crazy guy with the
van full of signs that drives around
town putting signs up all over the place
I'm currently out on $45,000 bond for
putting signs up around town asking for
justice for child rapes taking place at
Lancaster football parties where the
former CPS director and current
principal's sonop for a second sir thank
you thank you right the Lights Went Out
in the back I just go ahead sir so I'm
here to talk about that today and let
you all aware that my case is going to
the Ohio Supreme Court this week I was
sentenced to 15 days in jail unless I
apologize to these coaches and it's not
happening so the Supreme Court's going
to be asked to take jurisdiction of the
case and I also have a pending appeal
against the burries in the fifth
district and 12 criminal charges that
this lady is pursuing against me for my
signs of free
speech so this issue downtown is not the
big issue the issue is the pedophiles
going in our offices in our schools in
our courtrooms and this town is about to
have a Revival and people are here for
it
today the stuff that goes on
downtown it can happen anywhere as long
as you don't do it in front of children
these people aren't going to fight over
it you guys are stoking this by allowing
it and not enforcing the laws you're
sitting up here laughing and smirking
and you want to see these people fight
each other but it doesn't have to happen
and if you guys would just not do this
stuff around kids we could all address
the real issue and that's the pedophiles
in Lancaster
Ohio thank you for the comments sir our
next speaker
thanks hello my name is Aubrey and I
live on Pleasantville Road I'm a parent
and concerned citizen I assume that you
have seen a repetitive image this week
and I wanted to show you another one and
bring us all back to
reality so do we ban football is
cheerleading considered obscene are
children not at these
games I watched a video that has been
circulating my children without my
parental consent from this Pride event
and a right-wing conservative group and
several horrific comments that have
incited violence against us which has
not put them in danger I hope that this
act alone demonstrates that these people
are not interested in the welfare of our
children or overall safety of anyone in
this community as a photographer I've
spent over a decade documenting and
compiling videos from Christians
Catholics and several other religions
wedding receptions from this area and I
have cinematic proof that this kind of
dance Ing and lyricss happen all the
time and around children the difference
is that no SP hateful spiteful person
showed up to protest and tell them how
disgusting they are all of the things
mentioned are one's personal preferences
and should be kept in mind for their own
lives and their own children while they
might not want to watch a drag
performance or take their kids to one
that is great and absolutely their right
while I personally don't believe in a
lot of religious practices it is not my
place to show up to a church event and
film them and talk about how gross they
are because people don't do that and
parents have the right to parent their
child how they feel is best imagine me
addressing this board and saying I don't
believe in church and I don't agree with
what these people are doing with their
kids I shouldn't have to see crosses
downtown or be subjected to
religious-based events held in your town
square I hope that you'd laugh me out of
this room because it is not my place to
attempt to ban things for others just
because I don't believe in them to
Circle back gymnasts ballet dancers
cheerleaders and any other individual
who performs wear skimpy shiny attire
and do the splits it's as if some of
these individuals aren't watching TV or
aren't aware of social events that are
happening around us this kind of dancing
and Performing happens at several
locations locally mostly by young
children at recital and no one bats an
eye no I think the problem is is not
what's happening or the actual actions
that they see it's who's doing them if
this was not an event for Pride this
would not be an issue and it is our
responsibility as adults to teach the
children in our community that is okay
to be yourself representation matters
and it saves lives rainbow Alliance has
been been a pillar for our community and
is representing countless of your
citizens who have not had representation
in the past because of suppression and
ignorance I read a quote last night from
Fairfield Family Forum that said
together we can convert the lost souls
to Christ and really make an impact in
Fairfield County enough is enough this
is our lives queers aren't going
anywhere neither are their parents their
families or their friends we are here we
will stay and we will not be intimidated
thank you for your
time next speaker please Vincent
cillo great thank you sir Kathleen
Porter hello I am here today really just
to say thank you to everyone here who is
coming here every month whether the
crowd is this large or much smaller who
is allowing everyone to have their
moment in time their events that they
see fit and you come here and you do
your due diligence and uh we show up
when we have something to say and I
think that we all need to think about
the fact
that things that are happening in our
community happen all the time and
everybody has a right to do and say what
they want as many people before me has
expressed but I would also so just
really wanted to take the time today to
say thank you to all of you because you
worked all day and then you came here
and you're listening to all of us and
everything that we have to say and I
want to make sure that you know that I
value that and I'm thankful that you
give all of us the opportunity to have
our voices heard
and that's about it I'm not as eloquent
as everybody else but I just wanted to
say thank you
thank you next speaker please Eli
schl good evening my name is Eli schl
and I live on L Rico Boulevard um I once
again want to address the council hello
everyone good to see you again um thank
you again for your time like my previous
speaker stated we appreciate you being
here um as I said last time I am a
resident of Lancaster I live here I work
here and I Prosper here me and my
brother are both members of marginalized
communities in the United States of
America and we both do a lot around here
you could ask Amanda Everett she has us
wrapped around her
finger but we do so much to keep this
community running and we do so much to
keep this community proud and I just
want to say that fear has no place in
this community we may not be a community
that agrees on everything but I will say
that we are one who allows space for
everyone and that was challenged on the
14th I'm
trying I'm really tired of having to
have this argument over and over again I
do it at school I do it at work I do it
here now before you um hate hurts and
it's not about what we do or how we do
it there's simply just going to be hate
and that's something we can't change
unfortunately so I'm not going to fight
on your beliefs your religion on
anything else but I am going to say if
you do not like what we have to do you
do not have to be there the event was
public but not mandatory the event was
love and we express that in many
different ways in our performances in
day-to-day in shopping with local
vendors with some really cute items um
but that's what we're going to do and
we're going to keep doing that I yield
the rest of my time
thank you all thank
you next speaker please Amy
schlik hello member of of city council
um most of my stuff has already been
said and it's been said very well by
other individuals so mine's going to be
short and sweet um if we're worried
about children seeing images downtown at
light the night that we don't want them
to see these same
individuals took those same pictures and
have put it all over social media and
all over uh areas around town even being
on individuals doors probably not mine
because I have a pride flag out front
but um if we're worried about children
seeing it guess what children are going
to see it on the social media or when
they get home off the school bus and
it's on their door and you've just done
the very same thing that you didn't want
us to do so I'm not sure why we're here
talking but that's it thank you thank
you next speaker
please Natalie
noes thank you members of council for
hearing us out today my name is Natalie
noise I reside on South tenant Street
here in lanaster I grew up here I went
to high school here in fact I used to as
part of Lancaster High School film these
very Council meetings and remember not
imagining myself in this chamber I stand
before you today not just as a citizen
and a taxpayer but also as the president
of the rainbow Alliance of Fairfield
County I was proud to take this over in
April of this year and my first 6 months
has been tumultuous to say the best but
I remain so proud of this
organization I cannot speak to the
numbers that one of the prior speakers
had mentioned for lgbtq plus youth uh I
was a youth who did not come out until
my years in college because of social
stigma so I am very proud to say that
now this is an identity I may hold and I
may hold publicly and I can also provide
education and entertainment for other
members of my
community the mission of the rainbow
Alliance is to Foster Community provide
education and host events open to all
members of the lgbtqia plus Community as
well as their allies folks who donate to
us are donating to allow us to keep
these events open to the public free of
cost with the cost of virtually
everything going up it was important to
us that we have a free event that
families could attend and had a
fantastic event I'm very proud of our
speakers from the Fairfield County
Heritage Association of our Lancaster
Pride choir which was phenomenal the
Columbus Pride band members who joined
us and yes also of the drag performers
who were there this was a lovely night
in downtown Lancaster with several other
local businesses also having events for
folks to attend and I loved knowing that
people could could attend a plethora of
these
events September is also National
Suicide Prevention Awareness Month uh
thank you to the chase Haley Association
who is always bringing this to light but
when we talk about suicide prevention
lgbtq plus youth are four times as
likely these are CDC records as of
2022 to contemplate
suicide so when we provide these safe
spaces it is harm
prevention it is allowing these youth
like me who may be questioned to have a
space that no matter what or how they
identify they will have safety they will
have community and we are so grateful to
have that community in our hometown of
Lancaster Ohio you've reached your three
limit three minute limit thank
you next speaker please Levi B
hello my name is Levi baros I reside at
706 South Columbus Street here in
Lancaster Ohio I have been a a lster
member sorry not member a resident since
2019 I want to talk to you as you guys
see I'm in in a wheelchair uh I uh want
to see if we're able to make the road
safer uh sidewalk safer especially on
the South Side I uh have almost been hit
in crosswalks for various reasons some
people not paying attention or in a
hurry uh or just not educated about
pedestrian uh laws uh or who has the
right away or who does not have the
right away uh secondly is the sidewalks
I flipped out of my manual chair the one
I'm in right now multiple times on
uneven sidewalks um or even Crossing uh
streets um I have actually almost
flipped out of my power chair which is
got bigger tires as well um due to
having uneven uh sidewalks and stuff uh
South Columbus Street uh past um the
Canal Street has no sidewalks at all
I've almost been hit four different
times now since the two years I've
utilized this
wheelchair uh another thing is I'm a
sports enthusiast
so the skate park that I hear we are
looking to get um I'm wanting to know if
I'm able to be a part of that U like
building it uh since I am since I
utilize the one that we have now
um so newwork Ohio has a really good
skate park it's accessible for
wheelchair users and uh myself go there
a lot uh hopefully I did not um go over
my 3 minutes and thank you for the
opportunity to speak and again thank you
guys for coming out after your work days
thank thank you sir you did not go over
your three
minutes next speaker
please the next speaker is Alicia Curry
but she does not reside in the city
limits does she pay income tax work at a
building in the city limits
Etc good evening no um I was born and
raised in lingster but I don't reside
here now so out of respect for the rules
of the council I'll seed my time thank
you thank you ma'am next speaker please
Robert
nisle thank you Mr President um I think
that a lot of things have already been
said so I'll keep it I'll keep it short
um you know I I I don't hate anybody I
don't think that the God that I serve
hates anybody um I uh I have nothing but
love for everyone especially The Unborn
for kids um you know and and I I I'm
speaking as a resident of lanaster a
father myself um I really want um I
really want kids to just be protected in
this town and I think that what happened
on September 14th now I was there um at
light the night I think the vast
majority of the night I think most of us
would agree uh went off it was fine
there were people talking there were
vendors speakers like that's you know
first amendment all the way that's
totally fine um but there were there
were just a couple performers I think
that performed later on that had minimal
clothing that were doing Special um
routines that were Expos not exposing
themselves in a way that I think could
be sexual in nature there were children
handing these men money um sometimes
putting it in garments handing it to
them things like that um and uh I you
know I I firmly believe that that this
kind of activity um while I may not
agree with it if it were to happen on
private property there's nothing I can
do about that and I think that most of
us would agree I think the main issue
that a lot of us have is that this
happened on a public park in the middle
of town in the middle of the day and uh
you know something that um children
should not have seen that should not
have been exposed to I think there are
public indecency laws already in the
books that should have been enforced
that were not and I think that's a shame
and I hope that this Council will look
at this in the future and address these
problems and make sure that those types
of performances don't happen again and
that's all I have thank you thank you
sir next speaker please Teresa
Speakman hello I'm Teresa Speakman a
lifelong resident of Lancaster parent
parent small business owner and Elder
I'm here today in solidarity with the
rainbow Alliance of Fairfield County who
sponsored light the night with pride
event on September 14th and the 31 safe
spaces that are vetted by the rainbow
Alliance of Fairfield County my business
mud Gallery is
included I want to address the video
footage taken by a member of the
Fairfield County conservatives Facebook
group group in which they seem to focus
on a split second shot that showed the
performer uh with split legs up in the
air when focusing on one scene one does
not get the complete picture of the
show first of all as an artist and
gallery owner I can say that the drag
show is performance
art including dancing doing the splits
break dancing which was awesome and
general pre around as one would see in a
beauty pageant and many other events
whether a musical concert gymnastics and
the end NFL cheerleading while why
somebody else showed the um picture this
is an example of one shot of the
Minnesota Vikings cheerleading
performance in the uh
2016 which was I eliminated the
background because I'm cheap on
ink um and that was was in 2016 which
shows it's been accepted that a woman
can perform like this for a long time a
woman uh I know as one of my daughters
performed with the Lancaster High School
cheerleading competition in Florida a
few years back I'm deeply concerned for
the potential violence that could result
from the hateful racist and anti-gay
comments that have being spewed by some
members of the Fairfield County
conservatives and Fairfield Family Forum
Facebook groups that are most likely
present here this evening some comments
State God hates
and are focused on businesses that
are safe spaces and creating stories
that these businesses are grooming
children to be gay as if that was
possible and our
pedophiles I'm aware that this slander P
perhaps not the scope of what our city
council engages in dealing with but it's
certainly something that I think should
be made aware of I also know as human
beings we all have needs we all share
the same needs uh like safety Community
being heard being loved but we all have
different strategies to achieve
that thank
you thank
you law director Hall how many do we
have left for public comment
purposes 12 12 so ladies and gentlemen I
know you've heard a lot tonight we're at
um 20 till 8 we're not trying to limit
comment but if you've said something or
heard if your plan was to get up and say
something that's already been said
believe me we we've heard it we're
listening we've all your
correspondents um but we just want to
make sure and be respectful of folks
time so um we'll continue uh with
comment now keeping that in mind law
director Hall who's our next speaker it
is Sarah Mullins
hi uh my name is Sarah Mullins and I'm a
lifelong resident of lanaster I have
also worked and volunteered in our
amazing downtown
area uh I'm also a straight woman of
Christian faith just in case that
matters uh I want to start by saying
that the pride event was wonderful it
brought together a community that put
love above all else and you could just
feel the happiness in the air that was
until the protesters showed up using
fear tactics to make attendees
uncomfortable I wish I could say their
present didn't affect me but
unfortunately it did They Carried bags
that purposely looked like they
contained guns which was confirmed when
I overheard two of them talking as I was
leaving commenting about how great of an
idea it was to do
that their fear tactics worked on me and
others some of us were on edge for the
rest of the evening constantly watching
what they were doing eventually I had to
leave due to the anxiety caused by their
presence and the fear of how far their
hatred might drive them
especially after one of them commented
next drag show we need to do the same
thing as we did during the BLM protest
Second Amendment
encouragement I don't feel I need to
explain that threat any
further although you will hear about
children's safety tonight there was the
same protesters at the 18 plus ticketed
event at the faux bar the night
before uh that also hosted a drag show
using the safety of children is simply a
ruse to get their attention to the
public of their actual
agenda The Pride event was a public
gathering for anyone who wanted to
attend a place where people could enjoy
being themselves there was no nudity no
thongs no one was forced to attend and
those who hated the idea of the event
simply could have stayed
home please don't consider shutting down
a safe harm-free event that means so
much to so many people in this town it
is clear that the drag show was not the
threat in downtown Lancaster that night
thank you so much for your time thank
you next speaker please Jenna
Holly everything that I've wanted to say
tonight has already been said so I yield
my time please thank you next speaker
please Brian Lambert
thank you uh I was born and raised here
in Lancaster I actually moved away in
1992 and spent the next 30 Years living
in another town in Ohio that's made the
news lately um but I retired and moved
back when I first lived here uh
Lancaster was very U intimidating just
the word gay could get you beat up Sir
excuse me I mean could you put the sign
down you're Abu ing the view of people
behind you we we can see it we
appreciate it if you want to set it over
here in the corner you can thank you sir
you may continue
okay just the word gay could get you
beat up back when I left it was
refreshing when I moved back a couple of
years ago to see that Lancaster had
moved forward was a little more
Progressive and a little more
tolerant um I say a little more because
whether you're aware of it or not um
images from this meeting in the gallery
have already made it onto Facebook I'm
assuming in the hopes of intimidating
people to which I say if you're going to
use my picture get my good
site
uh the what happened at the pride event
was a nice Gathering I've seen worse at
Miley Cyrus concerts Madonna concerts or
even like they said in football games uh
please
do not allow fear mistrust and hate to
end an event that is trying to bring a
community
together thank you next speaker please
Larry
Reams members of
council today I found this in my door as
many of you may have found that and was
a little concerned so I wanted to come
here and see who was trying to stir up
fear in my
community a lot of stuff has already
been said but I'm going to focus now
just on principle because that's not
been covered First Amendment means that
you can offend me first amendment means
that I don't have to go there if I'm
being offended by what you're doing I
can walk away it's okay if you are a
patriot if you value American principles
truly do so then you will celebrate the
fact that other people are different
from you are respect that and applaud
that the second principle is for those
who consider themselves to be acting out
of their Christian faith or any other
faith that they have because they're all
looking toward the Creator
if you are of Christian variety you may
recall that Jesus himself only gave us
two Commandments love God hey easy peasy
the hard one though is the second
commandment to love each other and to
love each other basically means accept
who others are or how they choose to be
or whatever it's their life let them
celebrate it let them have joy as they
find
joy and don't let them come down on me
as to how I find joy that is the Golden
Rule so if you are truly an American and
value our principles truly a Christian
and value each
other we're not going to have this or I
should say we're not going to have the
fear generated by this thank
you thank you next speaker please Greg
Layman
hi my name is Greg Layman I reside at
1484 Tiki Lane and thank you very much
for the opportunity to speak here most
things have been said but I want to say
this was a really great event we put
together a pride choir we practice hard
and we sounded very
good The Pride band from Clum came down
they were excellent we've been trying
for a while now to get them down and
they finally came down and they were
great the vendors were all necessary
they were wonderful information that we
all could use and some people that were
selling some things this wasn't you know
a bad event uh as far as the drag part
goes I didn't go over there I haven't
watched the videos I guess some people
you know recorded videos of it I guess
for themselves or show to their friends
I don't know
but um there's a lot of anti-church
anti-christian voices out there but I'm
very very proud of my church and years
ago we decided to become an open and
affirming
church and this is our statement no
matter who you are or where you are on
life's journey Grace UCC being committed
in word and deed to all God's people and
listening to our still speaking God
declare ourselves to be open and
affirming we are a congregation on a
journey that includes all persons
embracing differences of age age gender
gender
identity and or expression sexual
orientation race nationality ethnicity
physical mental emotional ability family
makeup marital
status socioeconomic political and
Theological background we welcome and
affirm full participation membership and
leadership in our faith family all are
welcome here and we had a table downtown
you know that night and it was wonderful
talking to people and listening to
stories and stuff but just to let you
know there are are churches that do
consider that being gay is compatible
with being a Christian thank you very
much thank you next speaker please
Cynthia
Anderson I have no agenda I just want to
speak um I'm also sixth generation
Langster Fairfield County and I have a
24 year- old Grand grandson that is kind
of frightened I believe he's gay but
he's a frightened to come out but I do
want to speak of um the hate that is
being spewed someone told me about the
Facebook page of Fairfield County
conservatives this is a hate page and
one of the members that spoke earlier uh
did not speak his true what he says on
that page um I don't go to church
regularly but um they are spewing this
hate in the form of Christianity and
trying to force their beliefs on
everybody else and that just isn't going
to happen with me or a lot of people in
my family thank
you thank you next speaker please Rod
Williams thank you for calling me up um
I I want to respect the rules here I
don't live in the city limits um I would
like to just take this opportunity to
say unrated to you pull your microphone
closer yeah I I Rod Williams I live a
couple miles north of the city limit so
I you P do you pay taxes to the city of
Lancaster I don't believe so now okay so
I am uh I I I want to I want to just I
want to say unrelated to this
topic because Lancaster is the county
seat and I I don't really I'd ask you to
maybe revisit your rule about that
because it's it's thank you we'll we'll
note that comment would you please but
those are those are our rules I think
you'll find that they're very similar in
other municipalities where people live
uh for purposes of meetings but thank
you thank you for the opportunity thank
you sir next speaker please Amber
Stanley once again folks we're reaching
the end of the meeting and we do have
some business left so if you don't have
a lot new to say and I'm not trying try
to dissuade folks but you know just keep
that in mind we appreciate you good
evening ladies and gentlemen of the
council I am deeply saddened to be here
this evening however as a mother I will
never miss an opportunity to advocate
for my children their individual
identities and their safety the rainbow
Alliance of Fairfield County has spent
the past few years uplifting our
community and creating safe spaces for
queer identifying adults and children in
the area Lancaster appeared to be
growing and for the first time I was
genuinely proud to be part of this
community when she was four I was
blessed with my oldest daughter we spent
years unpacking her trauma and while I
knew she was queer way before she did I
was so proud when she finally came out
the first Lester Pride again was event
was her first out Pride the mother in me
beamed I was so proud as I watched her
fully embrac who she was openly and
proudly after all she'd been through I
was robbed of the joy of this core
memory though constantly looking over my
shoulder torn between watching my
children enjoy themselves and ensuring
their safety sh a truck come barreling
through because the queers were in town
square my son is not out by any means
unlike my daughter he recognizes the
fears and social repercussions of the
internalized homophobia deeply rooted
within our culture with his support he
has allowed me to out him here this
evening we lost his great-grandmother
earlier this year they were best friends
I couldn't tell you how many games of
yatsi they played over the years or how
many sleepovers they had to watch
chopped but I can't tell you that she
died never knowing who her grandson
truly was I ass assured him that she
would love him just the same but I could
see it in his eyes he didn't want to
disappoint his grandmother we all have
that family member the one who complains
about gay representation on TV or within
movies maybe the ones that make the homo
jokes maybe they don't say anything
they're just the ones that sit by and
idly laugh sometimes I can't believe I
was well into my 30s before I realized I
was queer but then I look around and I'm
no longer surprised they're not
completely wrong though these neighbors
of mine amongst the fear-mongering and
the vast array of iCal fallacies there's
a wonderful underlying message to be
heard here protect the children yes
protect the one-third of queer youth who
will be physically assaulted by their
parents simply for their identity
protect the 41% of queer youth who have
considered suicide simply in the past
year due to their harassment protect the
queer kids in our community who go to
sleep every night hoping they made it
through one more day and no one caught
on that they were gay as a community we
need not entertain this baseless hate
filled claims tailor def fit such a
harmful discriminatory narrative to do
so further perpetuates Decades of
violence toward one of our most
oppressed communities we are your
neighbors we are your co-workers we are
your friends and your families we are
the businesses you boycott while
claiming to support local we are the
churchgoers you ostracize with your
bigotry we are the police officers the
firefighters and the veterans that you
claims to support we are your mayor
carriers your teachers your Cashiers and
your Baristas were here and were queer
and we not knock one
back folks thank you once
again next speaker please uh the next
speaker is Reverend Keith mcdevit but it
looks like he does not reside in the
city limits
so sir I have to ask you do you do you
reside within the city limit yes 1260
Wheeling Road uh
Northeast thank you that's a church 1260
Wheeling is the parage oh where I reside
okay sorry yeah just being clear no no
you you got to do it you got to do it
um so a lot of us are familiar with the
Mental Health crisis going along with a
lot of our youth and we may be able to
name our children niece is a nephew that
I think about who struggle with anxiety
and depression it's it's really horrible
right now what's going on in social
media uh but I also want to lift up
these statistics that affect the
lgbtqia a plus Community
more uh says that
lgbtqia young people who reported living
in a very accepting Community attempted
suicide at less than half the rate of
those who reported living in a very
unaccepting community and this is from
the Trevor Project
as it was stated earlier uh the rate of
suicide is much higher among those who
identify as LGBT qia and some have come
up here with courage to say that they
don't feel safe in the community from
what's being posted uh and the uh the
rainbow Alliance has created that safe
space for them I realize not everyone's
a Christian here um that we all have
different Faith Traditions but if I
could speak from mine for just a second
that I believe uh in Jesus where God is
in solidarity with those who are
crucified uh God is in solidarity with
the orphan the poor and the Widow that
God Longs for life and I say that just
because when I was at the rainbow
Alliance I saw that uh in community I
saw that in youth who felt affirmed for
the very first time picking out their
flag that represented their identity and
it was beautiful
uh and so I'm very proud to be in this
city I'm proud of my church and I'm
proud of all those who stand up for what
I believe is the kingdom of God thank
you you next speaker please Ethan
door many aging Democrats like to say
that the radical politics policies
they're enacting are for the Next
Generation but I am the Next Generation
and a growing number of Young Americans
like myself reject your your this agenda
completely we reject a degenerate sex
driven Society we live in and build a
civilization and we want to build a
civilization that will make our
descendants
proud not some depraved Craven cess pool
of Filth that you guys have built we
reject a perverted childless ideology
that relies on The Grooming of other
people's children in order to sustain
itself a baren ideology is a dead
ideology these ideologies only work if
perverts are allowed to access our
children's minds and bodies we will have
none of it we reject a selfish
consumer-driven sorry wrong line wrong
line we reject the Boomer driven
degeneracy and bankruptcy that this city
council this state and Country have
built for their legacy you may keep it
in the future we will be the city
council and we will tear down every last
shred this filthy Legacy so that no one
ever remembers that you were ever on the
city council enjoy your delusions while
you have them and a day is coming and
not too long in the
future that they will be seen as the
Frantic scrambling and
screeching of sadly lost souls repent
while the time is now I I end my time
thank you
sir
nobody's nobody's answering
anybody uh next speaker please mark
Conrad my name is Mark Conrad I live on
Town Beach Avenue I worked at Fairfield
County for 21 years before I retired
born in Lancaster my dad worked at
anchor Hawking for over 40 years so
we've been part of this community for a
very long time I am also the senior
Warden of St John's Episcopal Church
downtown Lancaster right next to the
Gazebo uh I'm also a licensed lay
worship leader licensed lay preacher and
I specifically do the morning prayer
service 9:00 a.m. Tuesdays through
Fridays at the
church I personally and St John's as a
church including the clergy and St
John's has been part of Lancaster for
nearly 200 years are highly supportive
of the rainbow Alliance of Fairfield
County and specifically of the light the
with prayed event and other events they
put on WE hosted an ecumenical prayer
service of a affirmation along with
Grace United Church of Christ we hosted
The Pride course for their practice and
warm-up session before they performed
and we provided dressing room space for
the performers of the Jag show that
evening those performers were the nicest
friendliest people you could ever hope
to meet we had a young lady from our
church who was present when they were at
our church she's going through a lot of
family struggles of various types and it
was a very healing moment for her just
interact with those
performers
um and lastly I just want to we are we
are considered a safe Space by the
rainbow
Alliance so we're fully supportive of
them and the final thing I want to say
as a as a person the Jo and the
wheelchair I fully support his agenda as
well thank
you Frank Clark
my name is Frank Clark I live on Forest
r
Avenue sir never happen in our sir I ask
sir I ask you use your time to address
Council please okay I just want to make
sure that the you can set it down and
folks can see it know about this event
understood and to dispel all the lies
that was told um to the mic too the only
people that were bullied at their event
was us um they were yelling at us while
we were praying four of us in a circle
holding hands on Main Street they were
mocking us um one girl jumped out from
behind a corner in the dark um I think
she owns the mermaid goddess I'm not
sure but she jumped out got my face and
screamed um let's see the so the party
that love is love um it's only if you
agree with them is Love Is Love um if
you don't agree with them then it's not
love anymore they will mock you they
will berate you they will try to bully
you obviously I'm a big guy that doesn't
bother me I've everybody in town knows
me I've been around town I'm not worried
about it but so just take that into
consideration um they're saying they
fear never seen it safe space what's a
safe space um because they got a rainbow
flag on their business I mean are
we I have nothing against gays and
lesbians and agenda don't do it in front
of kids don't do it in front of kids
that right there was filth that's not
about being gays and lesbian that is
filth and there was little kids putting
money in the pants of these transgenders
that's disgusting um so I've got six
kids here they're going to be raised the
right way um shame on the churches that
are promoting this um I'm going to ask
everyone we've been good this evening
we've let everybody speak please do not
interrupt from the audience and please
do not address the audience can I get my
10 seconds yes you still got your time
thank you um but shame on the churches
for promoting it because the Bible says
Love The Sinner not the sin it doesn't
say promote the sin in front of my
church um or condone the event put
rainbow flags all over my church and let
drag queens dress in my church it
says Love The Sinner not the sin so
there was no fear provoking there was no
firearms and bags there was none of that
stuff that was said it's just a a thing
where they are trying to get you guys to
think that they were in fear so they can
promote their agenda and continue their
agenda I hope you guys will see through
this and realize that 90 95% of this
town does not agree with this they don't
agree with this perverted agenda they
don't agree with it in front of kids
I've talked to them I've been out I see
a lot of people so thank you for much
thank you
sir law director Hall nobody left except
for me okay ladies and gentlemen we've
reached the end of public
comment thank you for participating this
evening in an orderly way um public
comment is a time to address city
council and we thank you for you you
doing that this evening at this time I
would ask law director hall for her
comments uh related to uh the the U vast
majority of the public comments that
we've had this evening thank you law
director and thank you president Porter
I'm going to take this opportunity to
use the big Podium because they never
let me do that they always made me sit
there behind the podium so that nobody
can see me which is not a bad thing
necessarily I tend to let make a lot of
faces when things are happening um but
good evening everybody as you all heard
earlier I am your elected law director
and City prosec for those of you who are
citizens in Lancaster and Council asked
me to address you because many of you
have been asking them to enforce a
variety of laws um if you go back to
Civics 101 council is our legislative
branch and they do not enforce the laws
that is the responsibility of the
executive branch and that's where my
office comes
in Council has a lot of important work
to do yet so I'm going to keep my
comments brief you've all been very
patient and I appreciate apprciate that
and I know we're all here for the same
reason um the Cedar Hill Neighborhood
plan but I'm going to talk about one
thing um in depth tonight and that is
the light the night with pride event so
as we've all heard it was downtown in a
public venue um it was in Zan Park which
is surrounded by public rideway and
public streets and that Park and that
rideway are available to all on a first
come first serve basis and they always
have been equal protection of law
guarantees everyone under the 14th
amendment that they will be treated
equally the 14th amendment was enacted
specifically to to alleviate issues
related to discrimination and as Justice
Neil Gorsuch held in the Supreme Court's
2020 Bostock ruling it's impossible to
discriminate a p against a person for
being homosexual or transgender without
discriminating against the individual
based on sex therefore the city cannot
treat lgbtq few plus individuals any
differently than they treat any other
group that wants to use that
space what we can do is Place reasonable
time place and manner restrictions on
the speech and expression that occur in
such
places we have enacted laws they're on
the books they mirror the state law and
they all comply with Federal First
Amendment jurist Prudence on this
issue
sorry there is a broad spect of Legally
permissible behavior and I'm going to
say that again there is a very broad
spectrum of Legally permissible
behavior that is protected by the First
Amendment and that includes drag shows
generally Saturday's show was a bit
risque I never need to see anybody's
butt in public never ever regardless of
who they are or what they look like I
think it's completely inappropriate
personally but professionally I know
that there is a difference between
inappropriate and illegal they are two
different
things it's illegal to engage in public
indecency or participate in an obscene
performance in public though such
behavior is not protected by the First
Amendment and I'm just going to say if
there are any parents at home with kids
watching now might be the time to move
them away from the television if you
don't want them to learn some words that
are probably
inappropriate I wasn't present for the
light the night with pride event um
Lancaster did have two police officers
in attendance they did not make any
arrests that night because they did not
see any behavior that Rose to the level
of public indecency or
obscenity the detective who compiled the
pictures and video from that event from
all of those folks Who provided that to
the police department thank you very
much he brought it to my office after
reviewing it all he agreed he did not
see any instances of behavior that would
require the police to intervene or issue
any kind of
citation finally myself and two of my
assistant prosecutors reviewed it as
well and so you know we are all over the
political Spectrum in my office one of
them is further to the right than I am
one of them is further to the left than
I am we all three watched the same video
and looked at the same pictures and all
came to the conclusion that nothing that
happened was a chargeable criminal
offense we did not see anything that
amounted to visible genitalia and that
includes actual cleft of butt crack um
scrotum anus vagina Leia the works it
includes everything none of that was
present didn't see any of it it was all
covered by the performer's actual
costume there was no sexual conduct or
sexual contact sexual conduct is
actually engaging in sexual intercourse
of some variety we all know there are a
lot of varieties I'm not going to go
into all of those
tonight but there are it's not that
sexual contact is purposeful touching of
another person's aerogenous zones to
specifically arouse them them or give
them sexual gratification none of that
occurred either there was nothing in
those videos or pictures that showed
that there is a picture floating around
that shows a performer on the ground
whose legs are spread it is tasteless
but it lacks context the video from that
night shows that the performer in
question was in that position for a
split second while performing a dance
routine dance like speech is an
expression that is protected by the
First Amendment courts have held that
repeatedly I have no control over that
I've had several concerned citizens cite
case law to me over the past weeks I
appreciate that
effort
however some of the case law was from
the 40s and 50s it's obviously not good
law anymore I know what the law is and
the law is essentially the Miller test
I'm happy to repeat the Miller test for
all of you here tonight but I don't
think anybody wants to go in that go
into that and I honestly don't want to
get fined by the FCC for the even more
vulgar words that would have to come out
of my mouth to demonstrate what that is
and how this fails to meet that
test specifically with regard to um one
of the cases I believe it was Roth or
paral it says and they did it more
succinctly and that's why I'm going back
to this they said hardcore pornography
is what
qualifies if any of you have seen the
pictures or video this is not hardcore
pornography I have been a prosecutor for
the last 18 years in Fairfield County
and and I know hardcore pornography when
I see it this is not
it
so in
conclusion I cannot represent or give
legal advice to any individual person
here it is my job to represent the city
and the city's elected officials and all
of the city's departments and I I take
that job very seriously I enjoy my
job it's difficult at times I'm not
going to lie especially times like this
but I have answered every single email
that has been sent to me with questions
about the law with questions about what
is legal what is not legal and I'm happy
to do that I will do that for as long as
it takes to answer everybody's questions
and make sure that they all understand
why we're doing what we're
doing I want to leave you with one last
bit of info something to think about and
you have to ask yourself if if we're
willing to
disregard anybody's rights anybody's
personal freedoms then what's to keep us
from trampling everyone's there's
nothing I took an oath to uphold the law
we all did we all swore on a Bible
before we were put into elected office
that we would uphold the laws of the
city of the state and of the country and
that is what I am doing nothing more
nothing less that's my job that's my
decision that's my reasoning and like I
said before I'm happy to speak to
anybody who has a question about that
thank
youh thank you law director Hall thank
you everybody we are going to at this
time continue with the regular meeting
um thank you for coming and presenting
your comments and we're going to
continue with the meeting at this time
with reports of standing
committees committees um finance
committee minutes dated September 10th
2024 submitted by Mr wolfinger
Mr President i' like to make a motion to
receive and file the reports of standing
committees second we have a motion and
second to receive and file the reports
of standing committees all those in
favor please say I I I reports of
special
committees um I'm sorry there are no
reports of special committees presented
to council this evening we have no
public hearing we will now move to
tabled leg legislation there is none
unfinished business
any council member with unfinished
business yes I do have a question so
with this having you know what you've
said is there anything that we can do to
make sure it is inside though I mean I'm
not trying to prevent them from doing it
but is there anything that the next time
could be inside like the is there
anything that I'm just asking just to no
that's fine as I explained you know the
city parks and public property are open
to everyone on an equal basis and so as
long as nobody is is you know engaged
enging in a criminal activity we cannot
keep them from holding their their event
on city property like I said it's first
come first serve so whoever gets there
first and gets signed up that's who has
access to the park for that particular
period but no we can't treat individual
groups differently I didn't know because
of what that the act that I not act just
the dancing that went on the way you
know it was like it was if it have to be
inside because the drag the drag show
the night before was that's what I'm
wondering okay those are two different
issues um the drag show that was the
night before happened indoors right um
and that's a private event at a private
business that was ticketed that's yeah
that's okay separate and distinct yeah
from this thank you though thank you
council member tener any other
unfinished business at this time hearing
none we're going to move to new business
at this time I will entertain a motion
to appoint council member wolfinger to
the Sid board uh given the departure of
council member niser Mr President yes I
move to I move to make that motion thank
you do we have a sec and we have a
second at this time um could we call the
role
Please Mr alss yes Mr bisj yes Mr Mrs CH
yes Mrs hoop yes Mr lenberg yes Mr
skover yes Miss tener yes Mr Wing yes
and Mr wolfinger yes thank you council
member wolfinger we appreciate your
service on on the S board thank you
we'll now move to the announcements of
scheduled meetings I have October 14th
it's uh for regular Council meetings at
6:30 and October 28th at 6:30 p.m.
special meetings special council meeting
uh September 14th was um needs to be
rescheduled and reschedule needs to be
determined thank you we've got a
regularly scheduled committee meetings
um water water pollution committee
September 27th at 7:30 a.m. uh City Hall
1897 conference room Safety Committee
October 4th at 8:00 a.m. City Hall 1897
conference room Public Works committee
October 18th at 7:30 a.m. uh City Hall
1897 conference room and finance
committee October 14th at 6 PM council
chambers reading of bills IM Co
$128.6 and then IM Co again for
$114.2 Mr President I'd like to make a
motion to pay the bills second have a
motion to second to pay the bills all
those in favor please signify by saying
I I all those oppose same sign there's
no need for an executive session at this
time I would take a motion to adjourn
the regularly scheduled council meeting
for October or excuse me September 23rd
Mr President I'd like that to make that
motion we adjourn second all those in
favor please signify by saying I I all
those oppose same sign thank you
everybody thank you to our audience this
evening uh we appreciate your
cooperation and allowing people to speak
in an orderly fashion thank you
[Music]